[theme music playing]
[Arnaldo] Do you know you're trespassing?
This is private property.
Mr. Mayor, my name is Ivy. Ivy Aguas.
[Ivy] I've laid the trap.
All we need is for him
to walk right into it.
[Jepoy] If we look at the status
of her assets,
she can be an investor here in Ardiente.
Good work.
[Arnaldo] You can have this
property, if you want.
[Emilia] I want that house!
That house is ours!
That's mine! All mine!
[Ivy] What will it take, Mr. Mayor,
to make this property mine?
Dinner at my place with the family.
[Emilia] Do you know I've been
eyeing that house?
[Ivy] What made you give it up, Governor?
Arnaldo convinced me to let you have it.
[Ivy] I admire people like you.
Those who know how to accept defeat.
But I never lose when it matters.
Never? So, this was your first time?
[Julio] I don't see any reason
why you'd refuse my grandson's offer.
Of course, I still have to do my research.
And if everything looks fine,
I'll sign the agreement.
Rare jewel… Very rare.
But didn't you introduce me
to your brother the other day?
Believe me, Ivy,
you're not missing anything.
[Julio] In every family,
there always has to be
someone who's… weak.
[Diego] I've been thinking about this…
You look familiar. Have we met before?
You think we've met before?
[mellow piano music playing]
[clears throat]
Um… I don't think so.
I'm the type of woman you never forget…
after you've met me.
[mellow piano music continues]
Are you all right?
I mean…
I didn't think we'd wind up
in that conversation
when I asked the congressman about you.
Diego, I'm sorry--
You don't have to explain.
[Ivy] Okay, sure. That'll work.
Just email me the proposal
from Pandora Estates,
and I'll get back to you. Goodbye.
[tense music playing]
[sighs]
[Emilia] But I never lose
when it matters.
Never? So, this was your first time?
Arnaldo took his guest home.
She's pretty, but too bad,
she doesn't look interested in you.
Do you know anything about the export
processing zone Arnaldo mentioned?
She probably thinks
you're too old for her.
Listen, Raul…
I've stopped having people killed.
[scoffs] Don't make me start
again. It's going to be messy
because it looks like Arnaldo
really likes her.
[pensive music playing]
I made a mistake, Nanny.
I shouldn't have said that to Emilia.
It'll only make it tougher
for me to gain her trust.
It's just so hard to hold back
when you're in front of the person…
who wronged you.
It's so hard to fight the anger.
How can I get what I want from
her if she doesn't trust me?
Trust can't be rushed, sweetie.
But I know ways to gain it.
[crickets chirping]
Grandpa, you should get some rest.
[scoffs]
I like her.
You mean Ivy?
Mm-hm!
It was good judgment
on your part to make her stay in Ardiente.
She's smart.
She's beautiful.
Financially independent.
Looks like my perception
of women is starting to change.
You can use her.
That's all?
Every person we let into our
lives serves a purpose, Arnaldo.
It's better that at this point,
you've already figured out
her purpose in your life.
It saves you the trouble of getting hurt.
It's a dirty business.
It makes you do things you
otherwise wouldn't want to do.
Learn from your mother's mistakes.
Oh, well. It's been quite a long day.
[breathes heavily]
[groans]
[Julio] I will take your advice.
And get some rest.
You should go to bed, too.
Good night, Arnaldo.
-All right, Grandpa.
-[Julio chuckles]
[Julio groans]
[instrumental theme music playing]
[Ivy] Are you all right?
I didn't think we'd wind up
in that conversation when I
asked the congressman about you.
-[young Lily] You're hurt.
-[young Diego whimpering]
All right. Don't go
near the cliff again, okay?
[instrumental theme music playing]
[Julio] Looks like my perception
of women is starting to change.
You can use her.
[Julio] Every person we let into our lives
serves a purpose, Arnaldo.
It's better that at this point,
you've already figured
her purpose in your life.
[instrumental theme music playing]
["Wildflower" by Arnel Pineda plays]
[song fades]
[sensual music playing]
Good morning. Time to get up.
-Natalie.
-[Natalie chuckles softly]
Good morning.
Good morning. What are you doing here?
Seriously?
Is that how you greet your future wife?
S-sorry.
[chuckles] Get up.
Daddy and your grandpa
are having breakfast right now.
And I'm sure they're talking
about the political marriage
of our families.
Are you excited?
-I'll just go take a shower.
-[Natalie chuckles]
Can I join you?
-Sure.
-[chuckles]
[tense music playing]
[tense music continues playing]
[Pablo] Raul's not joining
us today, Julio?
Oh, I think he left quite early, Senator.
Hmm.
Well, you know, no rest
for the wicked, as they say.
[Pablo chuckles]
I'm sure he's just finalizing
everything for the campaign.
[Pablo chuckles]
I see you've finally realized
how much money is spent
on a national campaign.
It's nothing compared to what
we spend during local elections.
[Pablo chuckles]
Well, we will get the funds.
Right, Emilia?
Of course, Papa.
We're all here to help you
get to that Senate seat.
[Pablo] Of course. And you also
have our family's support.
After all, we're about to become family.
[Pablo and Julio chuckling]
[tense music playing]
[Pablo chuckles]
In due time.
Once Emilia's already
part of the Congress…
[Pablo] Mm-hm.
And when Arnaldo runs for governor…
Oh.
Everyone loves a royal wedding.
[Pablo and Julio chuckle]
[Pablo] You're right about that.
[Pablo chuckles]
[tense music playing]
[tense music swells]
[whistling]
Hi, Auntie!
-Oh, you're here.
-[Raul chuckles]
-Sorry. Did I surprise you?
-You're back so soon.
I'm sorry I didn't give you a heads-up.
Are you tired? Do you want to eat?
-No, I'm fine.
-Let me set the table.
I just want to rest a bit. You know why.
I can hardly do what I want
in the place I'm staying at.
I could really use a breather.
Then get some rest here.
I know you've had a long drive.
I'll prepare breakfast for you.
She'll get up soon.
Don't worry about me.
Just continue doing your chores.
I want to prepare
a meal for her. All by myself.
-Really? Are you sure?
-Yes.
-That's sweet.
-[Raul chuckles]
-I'll leave you then.
-Okay, Auntie.
-I'll go out now.
-Okay.
[caretaker] Okay.
That's good to go.
Joan, I revised the memo.
Make sure everyone gets it, okay?
And then update me, okay?
-Yes, Ms. Aguas.
-Thanks. You may go.
[sighs] Thank you, Nanny.
No problem.
Here.
Um… Any news yet?
I heard that
Governor Emilia has a meeting
regarding her foundation later.
Where at?
At her favorite restaurant.
[tense music playing]
Then I'll start with
the first phase of the plan.
Starting today, I will befriend…
Governor Emilia Ardiente-Torillo.
[tense music swells]
Let's eat. I made you breakfast.
[man 1] Hi, Governor.
[man 2] Good morning, Governor.
[woman] Good morning, ma'am.
[tense music playing]
-[Priscilla] Hi!
-Hi, ladies.
Hi.
[Emilia] Hello.
-[Christine] Hello
-[Emilia] Thank you for coming.
[Emilia] Hi.
[Rica] Hello.
-Hello.
-[Christine] So, Emilia.
Who's this woman we've been
seeing with the Mayor?
[Christine] Your son has been
going around town with this
unknown woman.
Does Natalie know?
She's just a friend.
She's actually from
Manila. A family friend.
[tense music swells]
Ivy!
Hi, Governor.
Oh, Ivy. What brings you here?
I might think you're stalking me.
Uh… I'd be lying if I said I wasn't.
So, why are you stalking me?
Um, let's just say, to make it up to you.
Because during the dinner last night…
I felt that I may have taken
something you really wanted.
Governor, I'm sorry, but…
I just really wanted that property.
So I thought maybe there's some
way I can make it up to you.
Maybe I can help in your foundation.
Of course, dear. Who am I to refuse those
who wish to support the Ardiente
Women's Association?
Come join us.
Ladies, I'd like you
to meet Ms. Ivy Aguas.
She's the president
and owner of Aguas Realty.
Come, Ivy, join us.
Christine, do you mind
moving one seat, please?
-Sure.
-I'd like to sit beside her.
-[Christine] Okay.
-Come, Ivy.
Thank you, Governor.
Ivy, I'd like you to meet Christine…
-Hi, Christine.
-Vicky…
-Hi.
-Nice to meet you.
-Rica and Priscilla.
-Hello, I'm Ivy.
[Emilia] This is Ms. Aguas.
Ivy. Ivy Aguas.
So, Governor,
how can I help your foundation?
Do you have any new programs?
We have a lot of programs, Ms. Ivy.
-Yes.
-In fact,
we're launching a mass feeding,
and then we have a medical mission
for the senior citizens, and…
What else do we have?
I think we have a benefit concert, right?
-[Christine] Yeah.
-[Emilia] Yeah.
-[Christine] Soon.
-Mm-hm.
Can I come, too?
Of course, Ivy!
We'd love to have you there!
-[Christine] Yes, yeah.
-Thank you.
It's so nice of you, Ivy. Have some tea.
Okay.
[Christine] This one.
-[Ivy] Thank you.
-[Priscilla] Okay.
[tense music swells]
Thank you.
[Arnaldo] Uh…
I'm going to the municipal hall
to sign some papers, and then…
That's it. After that, I'm free.
Awww.
-I'll miss you.
-I'll miss you, too.
I'll be with dad in his office…
Mm-hm.
…in San Isidro. I'll be back, okay?
Yeah. See you later.
-[cans jangling]
-[suspenseful music playing]
[door closes]
[jangling]
[melancholic music playing]
[Pablo] That's Arthur.
He's the key to the zero crime rate.
[Arthur] That's not true!
This place is pure evil!
There'll come a day
this town will cease to exist.
[exhales]
[Arthur] Jessica Vergara?
What is it, murder or rape?
[Dante] Both. She went missing,
was found floating
in a river a week later.
Before that, she allegedly
had an affair with Raul Torillo.
This town will cease to exist.
At the right time, the whole
Ardiente family will be gone.
[suspenseful music playing]
[chuckles]
Mmm.
Not too much, okay?
There's a feeding program later.
We might only have a few buyers.
They might even ask for store credit.
I guess Ms. Ivy's one
of the governor's friends now.
What?
[Filipino folk music playing]
[Loring] She's now one of
your mother's angels
at the foundation.
[Loring] I liked her at first,
but now I don't know
what to think of her. She's been rubbing
elbows with your brother and mother.
-[Filipino folk music playing]
-[clapping]
[Loring] I must've had
the wrong impression of her.
You make it sound like
Arnaldo and Mom are evil.
Oh.
I'm sorry, dear.
I didn't mean it that way.
I know you love them. They're your family.
[Filipino folk music playing]
[clapping]
[no audible dialogue]
[Loring] Anyway, who cares if
Ms. Ivy gets close to them, right?
["Sa'Yo" instrumental playing]
I'm sorry, just ignore
what I'm saying. Don't mind me.
[Filipino folk music playing]
[applause]
[clapping and cheering]
[emcee] There you go.
Thank you, performers.
Now I'm honored to call to the podium,
our beloved governor,
Gov. Emilia Ardiente-Torillo.
[crowd clapping and cheering]
[no audible dialogue]
Hello, friends!
[clapping and cheering]
Take your seats!
You can sit down now. Please, sit.
[Emilia] This has been
our annual activity, right?
But this year, it's more special.
My friends have also visited to help.
Let's give them a hand.
Stand up. Come on, friends.
[Emilia] These ladies help me out here
in the Ardiente Women's Association.
All right.
This year, we've been blessed
with another sister!
Our newest, dearest friend, Ivy Aguas!
Thank you, Governor.
Thank you!
[clapping continues]
Hello.
[Emilia] Enjoy your food.
There's more than enough for everyone.
You can get more food at the table.
[woman coughing]
Ma'am? Have some water.
Letty? Letty! Come here.
She needs help. Come here. Assist her.
[Emilia] Enjoy your food.
How are you doing?
-Is everything good?
-They're okay.
[Emilia] How about you?
Ma'am, enjoy your meal, okay?
Excuse me.
Excuse me. Is everything okay here?
Yeah, I got sponsors for next year.
That's good.
They'll donate canned goods.
-Oh, yeah? That's good to know.
-[Christine] Yeah.
[Emilia] And then?
[Emilia] Is everything okay?
-[Christine] Yeah.
-Everyone all right?
[Ivy] Eat slowly now.
Is she okay?
-Yes.
-Let me help.
Ma'am, you're coughing. Have some water.
[woman] Thank you, Ma'am. Thank you.
-[Ivy] All right.
-[woman] Thank you.
Take this. It's mine.
-[Ivy] Here.
-Thank you.
You can use it to cover your mouth.
We have to cut these into smaller pieces.
That must be why you're coughing.
-[woman] Thank you.
-Here, so you can eat better.
Thank you, ma'am.
[Ivy] No problem. There you go, ma'am.
-You're all set.
-Thank you.
May I join this group, Ms. Ivy?
Mr. Mayor.
-[crowd grows excited]
-Good day. Good day, everyone.
[man 1] Hi, Mayor.
[Arnaldo chuckles] Good day.
Good day, everyone.
[man 2] Hi, Mayor.
[Arnaldo] Good day.
[Ivy] Eat well.
Good day.
[tense music playing]
[Natalie] Yes, Auntie?
I just got back from San Isidro.
[chuckles]
Okay, I guess I'll join you then.
All right. I'll see you later,
Auntie Emilia.
I'm so excited. Bye.
[Arnaldo] Go on.
Please take all these gifts home
with you to your families.
-[Ivy] Go on.
-Have some more! Don't be shy!
This is for you, ma'am.
Of course, I'll give you one, too.
-[woman 1] Thank you.
-[woman 2] Thank you.
[Ivy] We still have more.
Give them some more.
-These are for you.
-[man] Thank you.
-Did you have a good time?
-[Arnaldo clears throat]
[Ivy] Oh.
No, thank you, Mr. Mayor. I'm fine.
I insist. I know you gave your hanky away.
Mr. Mayor, it's okay. Thank you.
[Natalie] Arnaldo!
[chuckles] Babe!
[smooches]
Hi, Auntie!
[Natalie] Your mom called me,
and she invited me here.
She told me to join you.
So, who's your new friend?
[Arnaldo] Uh…
Uh… Ivy Aguas.
[tense music playing]
Natalie.
I'm Arnaldo's girlfriend.
Mmm.
-[Ivy] Nice to meet you.
-[Natalie] You, too.
-I'm Ivy Aguas
-Hello.
I'm actually new here.
That's why we haven't met.
[Natalie] Well, how do you find it so far?
Have you been enjoying
yourself here in Ardiente?
I love it here, Natalie.
-[Ivy] Really.
-[Natalie chuckles]
I'm actually considering
staying for a while.
[Natalie chuckling] Oh!
So, you plan on staying.
Yes.
[Natalie chuckling] Oh, great.
Well, excuse me.
Okay.
-Babe, I missed you!
-Friends!
Our work is done, everyone.
-[Natalie] Let's go!
-[Arnaldo] Okay.
-[Natalie] Hello!
-[Emilia] Thank you, everyone.
Don't you know how to pass a ball?!
[kid 2] It's because you're fat!
[kid 3] And he's clumsy, too.
[kids] Piggy! Piggy!
Hey. That's enough.
You shouldn't do that.
You're hurting his feelings.
-Sorry.
-Let's go.
-Go on home.
[somber piano music playing]
What's your name?
Leo, sir.
Leo… I'm Diego.
Do you live here?
I haven't seen you before.
I'm just visiting my grandma.
Don't let those bullies get to you.
Even if they call you names,
don't listen to them.
Always remember, you know
yourself better than anyone.
Thank you.
I think I should go home now.
Okay, take care.
[Lily] I'll teach you how to lose weight
while still enjoying food.
See, you did it!
It was hard, but you made it!
Just tell yourself you can!
[pensive music playing]
[Julio] Your mother…
[grunts]
She loves to make decisions she thinks
is best for everyone.
But the truth is, they aren't.
That's why if it's not too
much damage, just let it slide.
After all…
Ivy's investment is in the works, right?
Yes, Grandpa.
Oh. Tell me, Arnaldo.
How did Natalie handle meeting Ivy?
-She got possessive.
-[Julio laughs]
I had that feeling, I did.
Is it hard to be so handsome, grandson?
Well…
What you shouldn't forget
is that Natalie is your future.
Actually, Natalie is
the future of this family.
We can't afford to lose them from our side
because we need them
at the national stage.
And Ivy…
[Julio chuckles] Ivy…
She's nice to have, but on the side.
It's like eating steak.
We have a lot of side dishes,
but never exchange prime beef…
for a measly side dish.
Remember that.
Cheers?
[glasses clink]
You're good.
[Carlotta] It's time to eat, sweetie.
The Ardientes are unbelievable.
They're so good at manipulating
people, especially Emilia.
She's only gotten worse.
She's rotten to the core.
[sighs]
I'm finding out so many
new things about the Ardientes.
But I still don't have any evidence…
that could link them
to my mother's murder.
Sweetie… You're looking
for justice, right?
It'll take you a while
before you find evidence.
But if you're after revenge,
it's as quick as one bullet.
Sweetie?
[tense music swelling]
[suspenseful sting]
[line ringing]
Hello?
I have a job for you.
[Emilia] Ivy, thank you so much
for joining us
at our foundation's fundraiser.
I really enjoyed myself, Governor.
I got to know more around Ardiente.
Hey, I'm sorry about Natalie.
Arnaldo didn't tell me
he hadn't introduced her to you.
I'm sorry about that.
Governor, you don't need to apologize.
Actually, I really feel
Natalie and I will get along.
That's good to know!
I invited them for coffee.
Want to join us?
I don't have plans, so sure.
I'll see you--
Okay, wait. I'll have
one of my guards drive your car.
-Okay, sure.
-[Emilia] Drive her car, okay?
-[body guard] Yes, ma'am.
-Follow us there. Let's go!
Yeah.
[Emilia] Ivy, let's go.
[car door closes]
By the way, looks like Arnaldo is here.
The guard dog is here!
Come, join me.
[Emilia] Is Arnaldo here?
[no audible dialogue]
[Emilia] Good. Come on, Ivy.
Emilia Ardiente-Torillo!
[tense music plays]
Your days are over!
-Governor!
-Gov! Gov!
-[gunfire]
-[screams]
[tense music swells]
Help her!
[gasps] Ivy! Ivy!
[Jepoy] Move!
-Stop!
-[gunshot]
[action music plays]
[Arnaldo] What happened?!
[Emilia] Hello? Hello, doc?
There's an emergency! Yes, at home!
[Jepoy] Get up! You bastard.
[grunts]
Start the car, hurry!
[Emilia] We have an emergency!
Oh, no, Ivy! Faster!
Arnaldo.
Arnaldo!
-[action music playing]
-[grunts]
Get up.
[man] Shoot him!
[Emilia] Ivy? Ivy, just hang in there.
Wait, I have to call Raul. Hurry! Faster!
-Fernandez!
-Sir?
What happened?
Sir, someone was after Governor.
But Ivy got shot.
What?
[Arnaldo] Hurry.
-[Ivy] Hospital…
-[Arnaldo] No, you're fine here.
[Dr. Hizon] Mayor, we'll take care of her.
Sir. I'm sorry, but you can't enter.
Is that right?
[tense music playing]
Are you okay?
[Emilia] Um…
She saved me. She saved my life.
[Dr. Hizon] Please clear the
area. We need space.
[Ivy groans]
[groaning]
[tense music swells]
Have you spoken to your father?
He hasn't been
answering my calls. Where is he?
You know him, Mom.
Doc? How's Ivy?
The wound isn't serious.
There's nothing to worry about.
You're gonna be okay.
Papa.
[Dr. Hizon] The painkillers
will keep you sedated.
But you need some rest.
I'll be on my way now.
Mayor, Governor.
[Emilia] Thank you, doc.
Stay with Ivy, Arnaldo.
I'll take care of everything.
[footsteps receding]
[tense music playing]
[door closes]
Idiots! You worthless guards!
[Emilia] Papa, that's enough.
Don't worry. I didn't get shot. I'm fine.
Shut up! I don't care about that!
That is not the point!
The point is someone dared
to go against me!
And I am the pillar of Ardiente!
No one must know about this.
The people will think I'm weak
if word of this gets out.
This will affect my candidacy.
Have you thought about that?!
You stupid men!
[panting]
Why didn't you take me to the hospital?
We have to be careful
during situations like this.
[Arnaldo] We need to be discreet.
We Ardientes can't let the people worry.
What if I wasn't just grazed
by the bullet?
What if it was worse?
Well, as you can see,
we have all the medical equipment needed.
You know, we can handle every
emergency you can think of.
Dr. Hizon is a good doctor.
He's trustworthy.
How are you feeling? Does it still hurt?
Ivy?
[sighs]
[tense music playing]
[tense music continues playing]
[instrumental theme music playing]
Such a naughty boy, Mr. Mayor.
Does your girlfriend know about you?
I'm sorry.
Governor?
Has my husband arrived?
I don't know, Governor. I just got here.
What happened to that man
who wanted to kill me?
We made sure to deal with him.
But it looks like
it's an isolated incident.
Uh…
The man didn't seem to be in his
right mind, so I got rid of him.
I dispatched him nice and clean.
Good job.
Thank you.
[Arnaldo] Mom.
Did you contact your father?
Not yet, but I'll call him again.
How are you feeling?
I'm fine!
Don't you worry about me. I'm fine.
[phone ringing]
Hello, Arnaldo. What is it?
[Arnaldo] Dad, where are you?
We've been trying to call you,
but we can't reach you.
The signal's pretty weak.
You need to come home.
Something happened.
All right.
[crickets chirping]
[somber piano music playing]
[phone ringing]
[line ringing]
[grunting]
[sobs]
[Natalie] Arnaldo, I'm talking to you!
-Arnaldo!
-What?!
Why did you leave me there?!
-You left me there to die!
-Can you please relax, hmm?
You were safe.
The shooter left when you came.
You still left me! Why did you go?!
What do you expect me to do?
My mom was scared,
Ivy was hit by a bullet,
it was an emergency!
So, is Ivy more important than me?
-No.
-Is that what you're saying?!
I can't talk to you
while you're like this.
Can you please relax,
go rest, or something?
I'll have Madrigal bring you home.
-No, we need to talk!
-Natalie.
Listen. Please go home.
Go on.
Madrigal, bring her home.
Arnaldo!
[pensive music playing]
Are you okay? You've been quiet all night.
I'm fine.
It'll pass.
Did something happen?
Nothing. Nanny, can I stay here tonight?
You weren't supposed to hit anyone!
I didn't expect her to block the shot.
They think you're dead now.
So leave this town and never come back!
Go on. Go!
[tense music playing]
[Emilia] I became a murderer
because of my love for you!
You didn't think how that affected Diego.
You killed his best friend!
You wiped out an entire family!
[Jepoy] Ivy, I know where
they buried your mother.
Where are you? I'm going there!
I don't care about
the Ardientes! Where are you?
[Emilia] About Ivy… Be careful around her.
I'm not sure if she's showing us
her true colors.
The Ardientes are here.
[Ivy] I want you to remember my face.
I am Ivy Aguas, and I am vengeance.